Hello OHBM 2020 Open Science Room!
I'm here with an update on the
MNE-Python project
MNE-Python is an advanced analysis package
for time series neuroimaging data
such as MEG, EEG, ECoG and fNIRS.
Whatever your needs are for
pre-processing your data
chances are good that MNE-Python can do it.
Let's take a look at some of the things it can do...
We can annotate bad channels
bad segments
bad epochs
and MNE-Python now contains a complete
implementation of MEG-IN's maxfilter.
You can compute independent components
so you can get rid of eye and heart artifacts
cut epochs
annotate them with meta-data
and study evoked activity
Any. Way. You. Like.
And when it's time to localize
the actual sources in the brain...
Perform co-registration between
your sensors and an MRI scan.
Construct BEM models.
Define a source space.
And compute the lead field.
And when it comes to the
actual source localization...
There are so many ways to do it!
Use cluster permutation testing
for group level statistics.
And so much more!
Now, let's take a look at what we've been adding
since last we saw each other at OHBM.
We've implemented the missing pieces
to make our open source maxfilter implementation
just as good as the commercial MEG-IN version
And this means we now support
continuous head position tracking
and correct for it.
You can use maxfilter for automatic
bad channel detection of your MEG data.
Our co-registration GUI
has gotten some love as well.
It will now attempt to automatically detect
the MRI fiducials.
It doesn't always work,
but when it does
your co-registration can be performed
completely automatic.
Our topomap plots are looking better then ever.
We've overhauled how we detect the head position
and deal with subsets of sensors.
And speaking of sensors...
You can now visualize
sensor-to-sensor connectivity in 3D.
We also support more file formats than ever.
Including: Curry files...
The new NYU 2019 KIT system...
And we can import independent components
straight from EEGLAB.
We're also faster than ever
with speed improvements all over the code base.
And finally... there's one more thing...
A completely new visualizer for source activity,
based on PyVista!
You can scroll smoothly through time
or just press the spacebar to play it as a movie.
You can quickly adjust color thresholds.
And click on any vertex
to get a plot of the time course.
But MNE-Python is more than
just a fantastic piece of software.
Above all, we are a community of scientists
sharing our expertise,
so that every one of us benefits.
Every time we solve a problem,
or find a better way to do things
all of our analysis pipelines improve a little.
Our GitHub page is always buzzing
with issues and pull requests.
Come take a look
and see what we're working on next!
Even better: please join in!
We encourage everyone to file new bug reports
and contibute pull requests with new features.
Alex and Eric are usually
the first ones to respond.
Become a contributer to MNE-Python
and you will improve your programming skills
you will make new friends
and you will find that when you put in some effort
to help other people
others will gladly put in effort to help you.
You don't have to solve every problem by yourself.
Come join us!